<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xpsl on congx.dev</title>
    <link>https://congx.dev/tags/xpsl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xpsl on congx.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 04:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://congx.dev/tags/xpsl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>XPSL Docs: Functional requirements</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/xpsl-docs-functional-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 04:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/xpsl-docs-functional-requirements/</guid>
      <description>There are 4 types in XPSL: user, room, track, playlist. This blog post lists the functional requirements for each of these types.
XPSL User  A user must have access to either Spotify or Apple Music A user must authorise XPSL for their Spotify and/or Apple Music account User can only belong to 1 room User can create a room or join a room once they have authorised XPSL to access Spotify and/or Apple Music XPSL will refresh Spotify access token on the user’s behalf Each XPSL user has a unique ID A user must have a display name A user could have a short name XPSL user client is a NATS client that subscribe to a XPSL Room (NATS Topic)  XPSL Room  Each room has a group of users who manage a shared playlist Room is a NATS topic that multiple users can subscribe to Each room has a topic ID of xpsl-room- Each room can have 1 or more users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XPSL Docs: Motivation and Overview</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/xpsl-docs-motivation-overview/xpsl-docs-overview-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 11:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/xpsl-docs-motivation-overview/xpsl-docs-overview-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Walking on the street, listening to a song you like, sharing that song with your friends, do a bit of silent dancing on the street, groove a little bit. Maybe you like that song your friend suggests, and wants to add it into your own music library.
Except you are on Apple Music and your mate is on Spotify. There are no services out there that offers a unified listening experience across multiple music providers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
