<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cong&#39;s little space</title>
    <link>https://congx.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cong&#39;s little space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 14:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://congx.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and shipping Hugo posts with Travis CI for Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/building-and-shipping-hugo-posts-with-travis-ci-for-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/building-and-shipping-hugo-posts-with-travis-ci-for-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>Since my blog source code is private, this blog post contains snippets of how I set up Travis CI to build and push Hugo&amp;rsquo;s public folder to another repository that hosts my public Github Pages.
It&amp;rsquo;s a simple solution, yet the top Google results only feature custom scripts 🤷🤷‍♀️🤷‍♂️.
Configuring Travis CI .travis.yml
--- install: - curl -LO https://github.com/gohugoio/hugo/releases/download/v0.59.1/hugo_0.59.1_Linux-64bit.deb - sudo dpkg -i hugo_0.59.1_Linux-64bit.deb script: - git submodule init - git submodule update - hugo - rm -Rf .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XPSL Docs: Motivation and Overview</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/xpsl-docs-motivation-overview/xpsl-docs-overview-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 11:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/xpsl-docs-motivation-overview/xpsl-docs-overview-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Walking on the street, listening to a song you like, sharing that song with your friends, do a bit of silent dancing on the street, groove a little bit. Maybe you like that song your friend suggests, and wants to add it into your own music library.
Except you are on Apple Music and your mate is on Spotify. There are no services out there that offers a unified listening experience across multiple music providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T.O.C</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/toc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 22:39:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/toc/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents? Yea nah, it&amp;rsquo;s a list of tags.
 Toddler - implementation of a Tribal Wars 2 game bot Keyboard - ThinkPad keyboard controller Music - song transcriptions General - anything that don&amp;rsquo;t belong in the list above  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>README</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 22:31:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/readme/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Cong. I am a developer advocate at IBM. I am passionate about learning new technologies and applying them to make people&amp;rsquo;s lives easier.
I enjoy writing articles and giving talks at local meetups and conferences. You can find me at IBM Developers.
On a day to day basis, I work proactively with clients across industries to implement and deliver enterprise IT projects using web and mobile, to cognitive and Blockchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Toddler plays</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/how-toddler-plays/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 16:16:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/how-toddler-plays/</guid>
      <description>Back when I first started looking into making the manager (like 4 years ago), looking through Github&amp;rsquo;s projects on automating Tribal Wars 2, I found most, if not all, of the projects relies on automating the browser instead of utilising the the game&amp;rsquo;s WebSocket connection. Therefore, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile to capture the essence of how the game client talks to the game server. Hopefully, this blog post may be helpful to those looking to automate this game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging with Papertrail</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/logging-with-papertrail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 16:44:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/logging-with-papertrail/</guid>
      <description>IBM Cloud is deprecating Kibana as a method to view Cloud Foundry logs. Moving forward, they are recommending LogDNA as a 3rd-party service. That&amp;rsquo;s cool. The process of logging Cloud Foundry is simple enough anyway.
With the general CF CLI, you would:
 Create a user-provided service with cf cups DRAIN-NAME -l SYSLOG-URL. Bind an app to the created service instance with name DRAIN-NAME as follows cf bind-service APP-NAME DRAIN-NAME.  Simple right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth of Toddler</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/birth-of-toddler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 08:51:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/birth-of-toddler/</guid>
      <description>Tribal Wars 2 Manager is now called Toddler!
Why? It&amp;rsquo;s a shorter name.
Additionally, there had been a few changes to project Toddler:
 RabbitMQ swapped out for NATS Project repos hosted on Github auth-svc is now called toddler-auth data-svc is now called toddler-world-data Elasticsearch is removed completely to simplify development World data is stored into a MongoDB database Deployment is sharply turned to Cloud Foundry - so much cheaper  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the basics with Cloud Foundry</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/beyond-the-basics-with-cloud-foundry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 23:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/beyond-the-basics-with-cloud-foundry/</guid>
      <description>The advent of Docker changed the way we develop applications. Once you had written a Dockerfile and built the image, your application will run (almost) anywhere, regardless of the underlying operating system, and best of all, it just works. You can then expose ports, map volumes to persist data and deploy your image in Docker Swarm or Kubernetes (K8s). With great flexibility, however, comes greater costs, whether that is increased developer&amp;rsquo;s skillset requirements and time spent on writing multiple K8s YAML config files, or pricier services on your favourite cloud provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There will be ThinkPad keyboard controllers</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/thinkpad-keyboards-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 12:25:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/thinkpad-keyboards-controllers/</guid>
      <description>A long long long time ago, finding an absence of projects on the internet to re-use a ThinkPad T60 keyboard to be used as a USB keyboard, I set out to research, make USB adapter kits and write documentation to this project. It was a success! I learned how to:
 Hunt down ThinkPad laptop schematics Design circuits in Eagle and eventually Altium Designer 3D modelling in Autodesk Inventor and rendering in Autodesk Showcase Send out PCB gerbers to abroad board houses for prototyping Write firmware for my first ever first USB microcontroller MSP430F5510 Develop a HID bridge firmware for Bluetooth 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribal Wars 2 Manager - Authentication Service</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/tribal-wars-2-manager-authentication-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:32:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/tribal-wars-2-manager-authentication-service/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I mentioned the 6 services essential to wrap up the Tribal Wars 2 manager: data collection, alert, farm, ops and build-recruit services. Before that to happen however, we need to figure out a way to talk to the game i.e. the authentication service.
Core service overview The source code for this service is hosted at https://bitbucket.org/cn-d/auth-service.
The authentication service is sandwiched between the 6 services and the game server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribal Wars 2 Manager - Services Overview</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/tribal-wars-2-manager-services-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 06:53:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/tribal-wars-2-manager-services-overview/</guid>
      <description>Merry Christmas everyone, and Happy Boxing day to folks in the Southern hemisphere.
In the last post, I wrote about the tech I&amp;rsquo;d like to play with for this project, but never really go into what each of the services does. This prompts the question to some of my mates who don&amp;rsquo;t play Tribal Wars &amp;ldquo;does this application need to be this complex?&amp;rdquo;. Besides getting all the tech in, what functionalities and services should this project provide to the player?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Talk to Ghost</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/add-talk-commenting-to-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:20:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/add-talk-commenting-to-ghost/</guid>
      <description>Back when this blog still ran on Ghost, I added Mozilla Coral Project&amp;rsquo;s Talk to Ghost, and&amp;hellip;
Legit, adding Talk to Ghost is not as straightforward as the documentation. While the Quick Start is simple enough on running Talk on your own server, what they don&amp;rsquo;t mention is the amount of overhead setup that comes with it. Being a noob to Ghost, NGINX and hosting a blog on my own server made the setup experience frustrating for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribal Wars 2 Manager - Architecture</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/tribal-wars-2-manager-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 17:24:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/tribal-wars-2-manager-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, I developed a single process NodeJS application for all the services in this manager (shown down below) and it started to raise out-of-memory errors due to Node&amp;rsquo;s limitation. This project aims to eliminate this problem by splitting the manager into multiple services.
This blog post serves a documentation for the high-level design of my Tribal Wars 2 manager. The development for this project is not about cheating in Tribal Wars 2 but using the game as a motivator to learn new technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this blog about?</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 12:12:01 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my fresh start to personal blogging. Back in 2012, I was a huge advocate for Adobe Flash despite Apple&amp;rsquo;s decision to exclude it from the OS&amp;rsquo;s and remote-controlled toys. So I started flashandrc.wordpress.com. After a while, my interests grew past Adobe Flash and remote-controlled helicopters, and evolved onto transcribing music that I like and making electronics. Soon, my blog became the go-to knowledge base for ThinkPad keyboards and Machinarium bossa nova guitar piece transcription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machinarium transcription</title>
      <link>https://congx.dev/posts/machinarium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 12:12:01 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://congx.dev/posts/machinarium/</guid>
      <description>Low-key, Machinarium was my favourite iPad game. It was an adventure-collecting game, where a little robot with his extendable arms and legs, going around his little world to collect items to help out his friend (I think, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while). In this one particular scene, when the robot enters a bar, there is this beautiful bossa nova piece. After a few fruitless Google searches, I decided to transcribe the piece.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>