<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IBM on Cong&#39;s little space</title>
    <link>/tags/ibm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IBM on Cong&#39;s little space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 16:44:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ibm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging with Papertrail</title>
      <link>/posts/logging-with-papertrail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 16:44:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/logging-with-papertrail/</guid>
      <description>IBM Cloud is deprecating Kibana as a method to view Cloud Foundry logs. Moving forward, they are recommending LogDNA as a 3rd-party service. That&amp;rsquo;s cool. The process of logging Cloud Foundry is simple enough anyway.
With the general CF CLI, you would:
 Create a user-provided service with cf cups DRAIN-NAME -l SYSLOG-URL. Bind an app to the created service instance with name DRAIN-NAME as follows cf bind-service APP-NAME DRAIN-NAME.  Simple right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the basics with Cloud Foundry</title>
      <link>/posts/beyond-the-basics-with-cloud-foundry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 23:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/beyond-the-basics-with-cloud-foundry/</guid>
      <description>The advent of Docker changed the way we develop applications. Once you had written a Dockerfile and built the image, your application will run (almost) anywhere, regardless of the underlying operating system, and best of all, it just works. You can then expose ports, map volumes to persist data and deploy your image in Docker Swarm or Kubernetes (K8s). With great flexibility, however, comes greater costs, whether that is increased developer&amp;rsquo;s skillset requirements and time spent on writing multiple K8s YAML config files, or pricier services on your favourite cloud provider.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>